ADR - Test Implementation

Context: We wanted to check is our API was working consistently and correctly. There are different scenarios and errors that we should cover completely, such as missing parameters, invalid formats and also valid requests . Therefore tests were needed.

Decision: we implemented local tests to ensure the API works as it should

The tests were mainly focused on 3 areas (the 2 endpoints and API key security):
1) Forecasts endpoint
For this endpoint, we implemented a comprehensive set of tests that validated the full request-response cycle under different situations. First, we verified that a request with valid parameters (id_well, sate_start, date_end) returns 200 status code, so the response contains the expected structure. Also, we focused on input validation, so we tested scenarios where required parameters are missing to ensure the API correctly returns 422. 
Additionally, we tested HTTP behavior, including non-existent routes (404) and unsupported methods lije POST (405).

2) Wells endpoint
For this endpoint, the tests were more focused response structure and parameter validation. We verified that a valid request with date_query returns a 200 status code and that response a list of wells. 
In terms of validation, we tested cases where date_query is missing or incorrectly formatted and it returns 422. As we did with the forecast endpoint, a verification of unsupported HTTP methods returns 405 was added.

To simplify theses tests of the 2 endpoints we used dependency overrides for the API Key.

3) API key security
For security, we directly tested the get_api_hey function to ensure it behaves correctly when received a valid key, an invalid key or not a key at all. In all the invalid cases the HTTPException raised correctly returning status 403.
Requests with valid key returned 200 status code.
We also checked the correct error message shown to the client was the one written by us. 


